♪Minum ibun♪
♪最小伊文♪
♪Your roots are holding tight♪
♪你的根紧紧抓住♪
♪On this land♪
♪在这片土地上♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪门格贾尔·姆巴克♪
♪My leaves fly by♪
♪我的树叶飞过♪
♪The border of thousands of stones♪
♪数千块石头的边界♪
♪Looking at each other from afar♪
♪远远地看着对方♪
♪The edge of the cliff is♪
♪悬崖的边缘是♪
♪Live together forever♪
♪永远在一起♪
♪When we meet and part again♪
♪当我们再次相遇又分开的时候♪
♪When we depend on each other and are far away♪
♪当我们相依为命 而疏远时♪
♪I never forget♪
♪我永远不会忘记♪
♪The light reflected on the sword and knife♪
♪剑和刀上反射的光♪
♪Light up the dim sky♪
♪照亮昏暗的天空♪
♪Abandoned dreams♪
♪被遗弃的梦想♪
♪Shattered in the wind♪
♪被风吹碎♪
♪Against the direction of the wind and waves♪
♪逆着风浪的方向♪
♪See thousands of ships crossing♪
♪看到成千上万的船只穿越♪
♪This world changes♪
♪这个世界改变了♪
♪A suit of armor with make-up swinging in the wind♪
♪妆容随风 摇曳的铠甲♪
♪Drinking ice, the blood is hard to be cold, dreaming of having fun in love♪
♪喝冰，血难凉， 梦想着恋爱的乐趣♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪只希望 你在我身边♪
♪Don't waste spring time♪
♪别浪费春天的时光♪
♪Trees reach the sky, roots connect, your friends uphold justice in the world♪
♪树参天，根相连， 朋友主持天下正义♪
♪Seeing the light flickering on the shoulder♪
♪看到肩膀上闪烁的光芒♪
♪No regrets in this world♪
♪这世上没有遗憾♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=爱的仙境=
=Episode 24=
=第24集=
(Boundary Barrel)
（边界桶）
Governor.
州长。
Already sent them?
已经发送了吗？
When Mrs. Wei got into the vehicle,
当魏女士上车时，
he was reluctant to leave here.
他舍不得离开这里。
He cried sadly
他伤心地哭了
and wanted to accompany the governor
并想陪伴州长
to remain on the Tong Border.
留在塘边境。
I advise madam
我建议女士
to take good care of the young master.
好好照顾少爷。
After this war is over,
这场战争结束后，
they will be brought back here.
他们将被带回这里。
Kali ini, Tentera Zhenxi
Kali ini, Tentera Zhenxi
conspired with the Cui Family Army.
与崔家军合谋。
This war will determine life and death.
这场战争 将决定生死。
It will end.
一切都会结束。
Somewhat
有些
we will not come back here again.
我们不会再回到这里。
(West Door)
(西门)
Chang'er.
嫦儿。
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
One two three.
一二三。
(Boundary Barrel)
（边界桶）
Governor. The Zhenxi Army allied with the Cui Family Army
州长。镇西军 与崔家军结盟
and attack here.
并攻击这里。
We protect you first.
我们首先保护你。
As long as we live,
只要我们还活着，
we still have a chance.
我们还有机会。
Go?
去？
Where else can we go?
我们还能去哪里？
Exit the Capital City of Xichang
离开省会西昌
and escaped from the Tong Border.
并逃出潼境。
Now, we're out of the Barrel Border again.
现在，我们 又走出了桶状边境。
Where else can we go?
我们还能去哪里？
Governor.
州长。
The Zhenxi Army allied with the Cui Family Army.
镇西军 与崔家军结盟。
The enemy is many times our number.
敌人的数量是我们的很多倍。
If we stay at the Tong Border,
如果我们留在塘边境的话
we can still survive for a while.
我们还能生存一段时间。
However, out of nowhere
然而，不知从何而来
The Zhenxi army entered the border.
镇西军入境。
How do we survive?
我们如何生存？
Both armies are fighting and now it is too late.
两军都在战斗 ，现在已经太晚了。
Governor, let's go.
州长，我们走吧。
During the Battle of the Han Sea,
汉海海战期间，
the Khagan's soldiers are ten times more numerous than ours.
可汗的士兵 比我们多十倍。
I lead the army to resist
我率军抵抗
and blood stained my battle shirt.
血染红了我的战斗衬衫。
I almost lost one of my arms.
我差点失去了一只手臂。
Didn't I still win?
我不是还赢了吗？
There are tens of thousands of soldiers in the city
城内有数万士兵
still against the enemy.
仍对敌。
I can't ignore them.
我不能忽视他们。
I will not go
我不会去
Bring his great-grandson here.
带着他的曾孙来这里。
Of.
的。
Sun Jing.
Sun Jing.
It's reached this stage,
已经到了这个阶段了
you still refuse to give up?
你还不肯放弃吗？
Come on.
快点。
Now, the Tong border has been invaded.
如今，潼边境已被入侵。
You will definitely lose.
你肯定会输。
If you release his great-grandson,
如果你释放他的曾孙
i won't kill you
我不会杀你
On that day, your father
那天，你的父亲
crawling and pleading in front of me.
在我面前爬行并恳求。
If he didn't pretend to be dead and run away,
如果他不是装死 逃跑的话
he has no chance
他没有机会
to be the illegitimate emperor in the capital.
成为京城的私生子。
Today, his great-grandson is in my hands.
今天，他的曾孙 就在我手里了。
I am the rightful emperor.
我是合法的皇帝。
In your words,
用你的话来说，
do you want me to hand over his great-grandson?
你想让我交出他的曾孙吗？
What do you want?
你想要什么？
You and your army
你和你的军队
retreat from the Tong Border now.
现在就从潼边境撤退。
Tell the illegitimate emperor in the capital to issue orders
告诉京城的私生子发号施令
and tell everyone
并告诉大家
that he ascended the throne in the wrong way.
他以错误的方式登上了王位。
He will return the throne to his great-grandson.
他将把王位还给 他的曾孙。
Given the current state of border warfare,
鉴于 目前边境战事状况，
it feels like you
感觉就像你
not worth negotiating with me.
不值得和我谈判。
Mari.
马里。
(West Door)
(西门)
Li Ni.
李妮.
This boy is the only one
这个男孩是唯一的一个
descendant of the late crown prince.
已故皇太子的后裔。
In your Li Family,
在你们李家，
he is the only legitimate descendant.
他是唯一合法的后裔。
If he were killed today,
如果他今天被杀的话
how do you want to be responsible
你想如何负责
in front of everyone?
当着大家的面？
how is your father,
你父亲好吗，
illegitimate emperor
私生子
should be responsible?
应该负责吗？
Do not mind me!
别管我！
Kill Rebel Sun!
杀死叛逆太阳！
Restore the peace of the country!
恢复国家的和平！
Kill him!
杀了他！
Sun Jing!
Sun Jing!
You are a famous warrior.
你是一位著名的战士。
I didn't think you considered a little boy as your protector!
没想到你竟然把一个小男孩 当成你的保护人！
You will be laughed at.
你会被嘲笑的。
No need to stimulate me.
不需要刺激我。
If you don't back down,
如果你不退缩
I will act.
我会行动。
Stop!
停止！
I will save his great-grandson
我会救他的曾孙
at the cost of my life.
以我的生命为代价。
- Tuan Shiqi!
- Tuan Shiqi!
Mr. Shiqi, you can't do that!
十七先生，你不能这么做！
Do not mind me.
别管我。
Jangan, Tuan Shiqi.
Jangan, Tuan Shiqi.
Kill Rebel Sun, recover...
杀死反叛太阳，恢复...
Tuan Shiqi!
Tuan Shiqi!
Don't be like that. Back here.
别这样。回到这里。
Okay.
好的。
King Qin is really brave.
秦王真是勇敢啊。
I will keep my promise.
我会遵守诺言。
King of Qin.
秦王。
Kill yourself.
自杀吧。
Master Shiqi, don't be like that!
十七少爷，你别这样啊！
Tuan Shiqi!
Tuan Shiqi!
- Master Shiqi! - Just attack!
——士奇大师！ - 只要攻击！
Abang Shiqi. Jangan!
Abang Shiqi. Jangan!
Jangan, Abang Shiqi!
Jangan, Abang Shiqi!
Don't!
不！
Tuan Shiqi, jangan!
Tuan Shiqi, jangan!
King of Qin.
秦王。
His great-grandson on Sun Jing's side is fake.
他孙敬那边的曾孙 是假的。
The boy I brought here
我带来这里的男孩
then his great-grandson is true.
那么他的曾孙是真的。
What?
什么？
Li Ni.
李妮.
It's okay if you refuse to save his great-grandchild.
如果你不救他的曾孙也没关系。
You don't have to play evil tricks.
你没必要玩恶作剧。
You want to use a fake great-grandson
你想用 一个假曾孙
to get a chance
得到一个机会
kill his great-grandson legally.
合法地杀死他的曾孙。
Governor.
州长。
You mean, this boy I brought is his fake great-grandson?
你是说，我带来的这个男孩 是他的假曾孙？
How do you prove it?
你如何证明这一点？
that you captured the real great-grandson?
你 抓到了真正的曾孙？
His great-grandson has
他的曾孙有
seal of the late crown prince.
已故皇太子的印章。
I robbed people and their seals
我抢劫了人们和他们的印章
from Han Chang.
来自韩昌。
If you're in doubt,
如果你有疑问，
no need to negotiate anymore.
无需再谈判了。
I will continue to kill him.
我会继续杀掉他。
Stop. Put down your knife!
停止。放下你的刀！
Take action. Governor.
采取行动。州长。
The governor never doubted
州长从未怀疑过
Panglima Yunchang, Han Chang?
Panglima Yunchang, Han Chang?
He was the old nobleman of the late crown prince who was so obedient.
他就是已故太子的老贵族， 如此听话。
After you kidnapped his great-grandson,
你绑架了他的曾孙之后
why is he not tracking you?
他为什么不跟踪你？
and gather people to save his great-grandson?
并召集人 来救他的曾孙？
The seal of the late crown prince,
已故皇太子的印章，
mengapa Panglima Yunchang
mengapa Panglima Yunchang
put it down
放下它
on this boy?
在这个男孩身上？
He won't know
他不会知道
that you can identify
你可以识别的
the identity of this boy
这个男孩的身份
after getting this thing.
得到这个东西后。
There is indeed a possibility of that.
确实有这种可能性。
All soldiers will be promoted and given a reward of ten thousand tahil
所有士兵将获得晋升并 奖励一万塔希尔
after killing Sun Jing!
杀了孙靖之后！
Attack!
攻击！
Take his great-grandson to go first.
带着他的曾孙先走。
He's still useful.
他还是有用的
His great-grandson.
他的曾孙。
Fifth Han.
第五何。
It's ok.
没关系。
I came to save you.
我是来救你的。
Come on.
快点。
Sun Jing.
Sun Jing.
On the day you killed the emperor,
杀皇帝那天，
have you ever imagined
你有没有想象过
that you will be defeated badly?
你 会被打败得很惨吗？
King of Qin.
秦王。
Keep killing
继续杀戮
just such a rebel.
就是这样一个叛逆者。
I am highly skilled.
我技术高超。
If I hadn't been poisoned,
如果我没有中毒的话
no matter how many people
无论有多少人
not comparable to me
无法与我相比
Ignorant boy.
无知的男孩。
Don't you try to kill me.
你别想杀我。
I won't let you do it.
我不会让你这么做的。
This pair of jed counters
这对jed专柜
really smooth
真的很顺利
One person takes half.
一个人占一半。
I will use it forever.
我将永远使用它。
I will not ignore you.
我不会忽视你的。
We will not be separated.
我们不会分离。
(In the first year of Tiantai, Dayu Dynasty,)
（大禹朝天台元年 ）
(Sun Jing is defeated at the Tong Border)
（孙敬败于潼关）
(and killed himself.)
（并自杀了。）
(His wife, Mrs. Wei)
（其妻魏夫人）
(and his eldest son)
（和他的大儿子）
(caught on the run.)
（在逃亡中被抓获。）
(Since then, Sun Jing's rebellion)
（从此，孙敬之乱）
(completely sedated.)
（完全镇静。）
Be careful.
当心。
Take it there.
把它带到那里。
Mari.
马里。
How?
如何？
- Slowly. - We go there.
- 慢慢地。 - 我们去那里。
Save this.
保存这个。
Put it there.
把它放在那里。
Slowly.
慢慢地。
- Come on. - Let me help.
- 快点。 - 让我来帮忙。
There's more there.
还有更多。
Mari.
马里。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Why?
为什么？
Someone kidnapped his great-grandson in the chaos earlier.
刚才的混乱之中，有人绑架了他的曾孙。
- Quickly tell people to chase him. - Yes.
- 赶紧叫人去追他。 - 是的。
How about King Qin?
秦王呢？
Let me tell him.
让我告诉他。
Go away.
离开。
Good.
好的。
Ying.
莹。
You are struggling.
你正在挣扎。
With your help,
在您的帮助下，
only then did I find his real great-grandson.
直到那时我才找到 他真正的曾孙。
Now, Sun Jing is dead.
现在，孙靖已经死了。
We just need to bring his great-grandson
我们只需要把他的曾孙带过来
back to the palace
回到宫殿
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
I must reveal something
我必须透露一些事情
against you
针对你
The boy I brought
我带来的男孩
is fake.
是假的。
His real great-grandson
他真正的曾孙
indeed the boy kidnapped by Sun Jing.
确实是被孙静绑架的男孩。
I have arranged people
我已经安排人了
looking for an opportunity in the chaos to save his real grandchild.
在混乱中寻找机会 拯救自己的亲孙子。
However, I don't think anyone acted first.
然而，我认为没有 人首先采取行动。
We must think of a way quickly
我们得赶紧想办法
and chasing his real great-grandson.
并追寻他真正的曾孙。
Shiqi!
Shiqi!
Wake up.
醒来。
Go away.
离开。
Let's count.
我们数一下。
Strengthen again.
再次强化。
Transport here. Go away.
交通在这里。离开。
Master Shiqi, we can't catch up.
十七大人，我们追不上了。
They were able to save his great-grandson in a chaotic situation.
他们在混乱的情况下救了他的曾孙。
Their actions are very fast.
他们的动作非常快。
Presumably they were Commander Han and his subordinates.
想必是韩司令 和他的部下。
It seems that his great-grandson is safe...
看来他的曾孙安全了……
How can we be sure that they are Han Chang
怎么确定 他们就是韩昌
and his subordinates?
和他的下属？
What if he was kidnapped by the bad guys?
如果他 被坏人绑架了怎么办？
I once made a promise with Mistress Xiao
我曾与萧太太许下承诺
to save his great-grandson.
为了拯救他的曾孙。
However, you brought a fake majesty's great-grandson
然而你却带来了一个假陛下的曾孙
to trick Sun Jing earlier.
早点骗孙靖。
Have you ever thought that if he trusts you,
你有没有想过 ，如果他信任你，
he might do evil things to his real grandchild?
他可能会对自己的亲孙子做坏事吗？
I used to think about it.
我曾经想过。
Since you know it's high risk,
既然知道 风险很大
why are you doing it again?
你为什么又这么做？
I have considered it many times in my heart.
我心里想过很多次。
I have 80 percent confidence
我有百分之八十的信心
to convince Sun Jing
说服孙静
and save his great-grandson.
并拯救他的曾孙。
80 percent?
百分之八十？
What about the other 20 percent?
那剩下的百分之二十呢？
It's good if we
如果我们能
can save his great-grandson.
可以救他的曾孙。
If an accident occurs,
如果发生意外，
it's my fault,
我的错，
nothing to do with you
与你无关
An accident
一次意外
is your fault
是你的错
and have nothing to do with me?
并且与我无关？
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
It must be me
一定是我
explain everything?
解释一切？
Don't you understand it too?
你不也明白吗？
If you really
如果你真的
brought his great-grandson back to the capital,
将曾孙带回京城，
state of the palace
宫殿的状态
will experience turmoil,
会经历动荡，
not?
不是？
I understand your thoughts.
我理解你的想法。
You want him to appoint his great-grandson as crown prince.
你要他立他的曾孙 为太子。
However, have you ever thought about this?
然而，你有没有想过这个问题？
Our country has just become stable and the people's situation is not guaranteed.
我国刚刚稳定 ，人民的处境没有保障。
Does everyone
大家有吗
will agree with your thoughts?
会同意你的想法吗？
Can the palace
皇宫可以吗
experiencing turmoil
经历动荡
one more time?
再一次？
You are full of justification and reason.
你充满了理由和理由。
Why didn't you consult me ​​first?
你为什么不 先咨询我？
Because you know
因为你知道
that I won't agree, right?
我不会同意的，对吗？
Of.
的。
His Highness is very brave.
殿下非常勇敢。
I don't deserve it
我不值得
intervened earlier.
较早干预。
I have to let you sacrifice yourself
我必须让你牺牲自己
and praised by all.
并受到大家的称赞。
When I pass through here,
当我路过这里的时候
I will too
我也会
burn incense for you.
给你烧香。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Everything is my fault.
一切都是我的错。
I could not save his great-grandson.
我无法 拯救他的曾孙。
Nothing to do with you.
与你无关。
I told you
我告诉你了
bring people to save his great-grandson,
带人 去救他的曾孙，
but I didn't think so
但我不这么认为
there's a scout there.
那里有一个侦察兵。
Somewhat
有些
they are Han Commanders
他们是汉族统帅
and his subordinates.
和他的下属。
Of course you can't fight them.
当然你不能与他们对抗。
How is your wound?
你的伤口怎么样了？
I am fine.
我没事。
Kata Is Duo,
朵朵是不是说，
King Qin scolded you in front of everyone
秦王 当着众人的面骂你
and argue with you.
并与你争论。
Don't mention his name.
别提他的名字。
Sun Jing left in a hurry.
孙静匆匆离开。
He continued
他继续
set fire to the entire reading room.
放火烧毁了整个阅览室。
Most of the items inside were also burned.
里面的大部分物品 也被烧毁。
I bring people
我带人来
find all this
找到这一切
under the rubble.
在废墟下。
Finally, I know that there are people in the drawing room
终于知道 客厅里有人了
conspired with Sun Jing secretly.
与孙敬 暗中合谋。
They are often in contact.
他们经常联系。
However, no name is written on this letter.
不过，这封信上没有写名字。
After all, they use secret terms.
毕竟，他们使用秘密术语。
So, we haven't seen it yet
所以，我们还没有看到它
this guy for a while.
这家伙有一段时间了。
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
After returning to Xichang Capital,
回到西昌京城后，
we still need to be careful.
我们仍然需要小心。
Of.
的。
Li Ni occupies the Tong Border
李泥占领潼边
and sent people to report him to the palace quickly.
并赶紧派人向宫里禀报。
He brought Sun Jing's body back again.
他又把孙靖的尸体带了回来。
All the dignitaries praised him in the ballirung seri.
所有的达官贵人都 在宴会上称赞他。
He made another big contribution.
他还做出了另一项重大贡献。
As his brother,
作为他的兄弟，
it's hard for me to compete with him.
我很难与他竞争。
It feels like the Eastern Palace
感觉像东宫
will fall into Li Ni's hands.
都会落入李妮的手中。
There is an extraordinary person
有一个非凡的人
want to meet the noble.
想结识贵人。
He sent people to fetch the noble many times.
他多次派人去接贵人。
I can't stand him
我受不了他
and meet him once.
并与他见面一次。
He said,
他说，
he has a great way
他有一个好办法
and can help His Majesty.
并且可以帮助陛下。
This person said his surname was Liu.
此人自称姓刘。
He was once Cui Yi's adopted son.
他曾经是崔毅的养子。
After I talked to him,
我和他交谈之后，
I found that his thoughts were profound
我发现他的思想很深刻
and have such a background.
并且有这样的背景。
This person must be hostile to the Cui Family.
此人必定 与崔家有敌意。
We can use it.
我们可以使用它。
I've been wanting to see you for a long time, Young Master Liu.
刘少爷我想见你已经很久了。
His Highness praised me too much.
殿下太夸奖我了。
His Highness will not want to see me.
殿下不会想见我的。
Now, I'm just one
现在，我只是其中之一
which is nothing.
这没什么。
Since you are nothing,
既然你什么都不是，
how do you want to help me?
你想如何帮助我？
The King of Qin took back the Tong Border
秦王收复潼境
and defeat Sun Jing.
并击败孙靖。
This is a great service.
这是一项很棒的服务。
After he returned to the capital,
他回到京城后，
it must be him
一定是他
want to get the East Palace.
欲得东宫。
As his brother,
作为他的兄弟，
doesn't the noble one feel the danger?
高贵的人难道没有感觉到危险吗？
My eldest brother is still there.
我的大哥还在那里。
Usually, the eldest son will be appointed.
通常，会任命长子。
Li Ni didn't stand a chance.
李妮没有机会。
What if Li Ni
如果李妮呢
married Cui Yi's only child,
娶了崔毅唯一的孩子，
Cui Family Army
崔家军
will obey Li Ni's instructions
会听从李妮的指示
seperti Tentera Zhenxi?
seperti Tentera Zhenxi?
At that time,
当时，
even the emperor
甚至皇帝
unable to handle King Qin.
对付不了秦王。
Even the noble can't seize the Eastern Palace anymore.
就算是贵族也无法 再夺取东宫了。
Even the honorable
就连尊贵的人
can't be
不可能
the prince relaxed again.
王子又放松了。
Li Ni will marry Cui's only daughter?
李妮要娶 崔唯一的女儿？
They are already in personal contact.
他们已经在进行个人接触。
If not,
如果不，
why the Cui Family Army
为什么是崔家军
go save Pei Yuan
会救裴媛
just with a letter from King Qin?
就凭秦王的一封信？
Why did Cui Yi surrender Changzhou
崔毅为何投降常州
just because King Qin promised
只因秦王答应
to bestow the title of Commander-in-Chief Weiyang worthless?
授予 未央总司令的称号不值钱？
Mengapa Tentera Zhenxi
Mengapa Tentera Zhenxi
willing to attack the Tong Border
愿攻潼边境
with the Cui Family Army?
和崔家军？
Oh it's like that.
哦，是这样的。
Actually, His Highness had already thought carefully.
其实，殿下 已经深思熟虑了。
Is that noble
那是高贵的吗
want to send people
想派人
to kill the King of Qin
杀秦王
on his way to the capital?
在去首都的路上吗？
However, the noble taste
不过，高贵的品味
is it hard
难吗
to kill the King of Qin who was below
杀掉下面的秦王
the protection of thousands of soldiers?
保护数以千计的士兵？
Young Master Liu has a good way?
刘少爷有什么好办法？
His Highness can take unexpected actions.
殿下可能会采取 意想不到的行动。
Start with Cui Lin.
先从崔琳开始吧。
Make him worry first.
先让他担心一下。
After he was worried,
他担心之后，
he will make mistakes.
他会犯错误。
At that time,
当时，
Your Honor can take this opportunity
法官大人可以借此机会
to kill the King of Qin.
去杀秦王。
This is indeed a good way.
这确实是一个好办法。
However, it is difficult to
然而，很难
implement it.
实施它。
Do not worry.
不用担心。
Since I suggest this way,
既然我建议这样，
I will take people there
我会带人去那里
to help the noble.
去帮助贵族。
Once this is done,
一旦完成此操作，
How can I thank Mr. Young Liu?
我该怎样感谢 刘小先生呢？
I do want to
我确实想要
serve the noble.
为贵族服务。
I don't want anything else.
我不想要任何别的东西。
I just hope the noble
我只希望贵族
move a group of people
移动一群人
for me to direct.
由我来指挥。
Many days have passed.
很多天过去了。
The King of Qin was inside the border
秦王在境内
and we are out of bounds.
我们已经出界了。
Logically,
从逻辑上讲，
not far.
不远。
King Qin is not making sense.
秦王的话不无道理。
He didn't come here
他没有来这里
and don't send people either.
也不派人去。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Speak up.
说出来。
Is the King of Qin
是秦王吗
really angry?
真的生气了吗？
Why are you so worried?
你为什么这么担心？
King Qin is angry or not,
秦王生气不生气，
what does it have to do with me?
这与我有什么关系？
Look at it.
看它。
You are really close
你真的很亲近
with the previous King of Qin.
与前秦王。
Aren't you
你不是吗
have a misunderstanding
有误会
for the sake of his great-grandson this time?
这次是为了他的曾孙吗？
Taozi, what's up with you today?
桃子，你今天怎么了？
You don't fly on a normal day.
平常的日子你不会坐飞机。
I just thought about this.
我刚刚想到了这一点。
Is the King of Qin
是秦王吗
become ill?
生病？
The weather has been changing lately.
最近天气一直在变化。
It was suddenly cold and hot.
天气突然又冷又热。
I heard,
我听说，
many people fell ill inside the border.
许多人在边境内生病。
Is Duo pun
是双关语吗
caught a cold.
感冒了。
If you are worried about Xie Chang'er,
如果你担心谢嫦儿的话
send medicine for him yourself.
自己给他送药。
So.
所以。
I will not go
我不会去
Lieutenant.
中尉。
If you don't care about King Qin,
如果你不关心秦王，
I won't even care
我什至都不会在意
Is Duo.
是朵朵。
I will not care about him.
我不会关心他。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Taozi, you finally came.
桃子，你终于来了。
What did the lieutenant say?
中尉说什么了？
He is still the same.
他还是一样。
I have been advising him for a long time.
我已经给他提供了很长时间的建议。
He also refused to mention the King of Qin.
他也不肯提秦王的事。
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
When I came here,
当我来到这里时，
Bao and everyone tell me
宝和大家告诉我
to ask you
问你
reconciled the lieutenant and Mr. Shiqi.
中尉和石奇先生和解了。
You don't know
你不知道
that Mr. Shiqi
那个世奇先生
really angry now
现在真的很生气
Before one o'clock every morning, he would wake up and practice swordsmanship.
每天凌晨一点之前， 他都会起床练习剑术。
He forced us to practice together.
他强迫我们一起练习。
We practice sword and spear every day.
我们每天都练习剑和矛。
If not,
如果不，
we will practice formation at the army camp.
我们将在军营练习队形。
We can't take it anymore.
我们不能再忍受了。
It's useless for you to tell me.
你告诉我是没有用的。
I also
我也
no other way
别无退路
to persuade you again.
再次说服你。
This is how.
就是这样。
The King of Qin ordered
秦王下令
pretending to be sick
假装生病
With that,
接着就，随即，
I can ask ma'am
我可以问女士
to visit the King of Qin.
去拜访秦王。
If King Qin is willing to pretend to be sick,
如果秦王 愿意装病，
he wouldn't even wake up early to practice swordsmanship every day.
每天他都不会早起练习剑法。
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
Bao.
宝。
How?
如何？
What did the Taoist say?
道士怎么说呢？
Taozi gives an idea.
桃子给出了一个想法。
However,
然而，
it doesn't feel right.
感觉不对。
If he refuses to pretend to be sick,
如果他拒绝假装生病
let's
让我们
let him get a little sick.
让他有点不舒服。
Give this to him.
把这个给他。
He will get sick after eating it.
吃了之后他会生病。
At that time, I will tell you
到时候我就告诉你
that the King of Qin fell ill and told him to visit the King of Qin.
得知秦王病了 ，让他去看望秦王。
This is not appropriate.
这是不合适的。
What is not appropriate?
什么不合适？
I think it fits perfectly.
我认为它非常适合。
Bao.
宝。
Is Duo.
是朵朵。
You don't know
你不知道
that Mr. Shiqi brought me
世奇先生给我带来的
patrolling late at night.
深夜巡逻。
At one o'clock this morning,
今天凌晨一点，
he surprised me
他让我感到惊讶
and told me to practice swordsmanship with him.
还叫我 跟他一起练剑。
I don't want to live
我不想活了
in this way again.
又这样。
Don't you want to take medicine?
你不想吃药吗？
I will take medicine.
我会吃药。
Bao.
宝。
It can't be like this. If...
不可能是这样的。如果...
If what?
如果什么？
If he doesn't get sick again,
如果他不再生病的话
i will go crazy
我会发疯的
It's better if he gets sick.
如果他生病了就更好了。
If not, I will really go crazy.
如果不是的话，我真的会发疯的。
Bao.
宝。
Place a sign.
放置一个标志。
Those who are pinched have medicine.
被捏的人有药。
What is not pinched has no medicine.
不捏的就没有药。
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
You've been practicing for a long time.
你已经练习了很长时间了。
You must be hungry.
你一定饿了。
I had the kitchen make this.
我让厨房做这个。
Eat it.
吃了它。
Are kitchen people good at making snacks like this?
厨房里的人擅长做这样的零食吗？
Isn't Sun Jing's cook
这不是孙静的厨子吗
still alive?
还活着？
I told him to do it.
我告诉他这样做。
Try the cuisine.
尝试一下这里的美食。
Look at this snack.
看看这个小吃。
Very delicate and beautiful.
非常精致美丽。
Try it.
尝试一下。
Look.
看。
Delicious.
可口的。
Delicious, isn't it?
很好吃，不是吗？
It's delicious.
这很美味。
Why, Bao?
为什么，宝？
Are you not well?
你身体不好吗？
Delicious.
可口的。
We are good friends.
我们是好朋友。
How dare you mistreat me.
你怎么敢欺负我。
Bao.
宝。
Poisoning?
中毒？
I used to be a counselor.
我曾经是一名辅导员。
How dare you add poison
你怎么敢加毒
in front of me?
在我前面？
You forced me
你强迫我
wake up early and sleep late.
早起晚睡。
We only practice swords and spears.
我们只练剑和矛。
How dare you change it
你怎么敢改变它
and tell me to eat a snack laced with poison?
还叫我吃 有毒的零食？
I want to break up with you.
我想和你分手。
I want to break up with you!
我想和你分手！
Young master.
少爷。
Really want to poison the lieutenant?
真的要毒死中尉吗？
Orang Jiesuo
Orang Jiesuo
give us just one.
只给我们一个。
He said, this is the most valuable secret medicine for them.
他说，这 对他们来说是最有价值的秘药。
After taking this medicine,
服用此药后，
no signs of poisoning.
没有中毒迹象。
People who eat it seem to get seriously ill.
吃了它的人 似乎会得重病。
Even the greatest healer cannot know for sure.
即使是最伟大的治疗师也 无法确定。
Without a cure,
如果没有治愈方法，
the person who eats it will die after a few days.
吃了它的人 几天后就会死亡。
If Ying didn't have any problems,
如果瑛没有任何问题的话
Li Ni will not be confused.
李妮不会糊涂的。
If Li Ni is not confused,
如果李妮不迷茫的话，
we can't kill Li Ni
我们杀不了李妮
and couldn't kidnap Ying.
也不能绑架莹。
Go away.
离开。
Be careful.
当心。
Of.
的。
Why, miss?
为什么，小姐？
Let me see.
让我看看。
I have been uncomfortable since this morning.
从今天早上开始我就一直不舒服。
My head hurts now.
我现在头很痛。
It's hot.
很热。
Must be a fever.
一定是发烧了。
So,
所以，
I have a fever.
我发烧了。
Bao.
宝。
Why are your skills backwards?
为什么你的技术落后了？
I couldn't beat you since before.
从以前开始我就打不过你 。
After all,
毕竟，
I have had diarrhea for several days.
我已经腹泻好几天了。
I have become weak. You didn't even let me go.
我变得软弱了。 你甚至没有放开我。
You...
你...
Did you really do that?
你真的这么做了吗？
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
What?
什么？
Taozi has come.
桃子来了。
He said, there is an emergency.
他说，有紧急情况。
I don't want to see him.
我不想见他。
Mr. Shiqi, he has an emergency.
士奇先生，他有急事。
What's the anxiety?
焦虑是什么？
If it's about the military,
如果是军事方面的话
tell him to write a letter
告诉他写封信
and send it to our army.
并将其发送给我军。
As an ally, would the King of Qin want to
作为盟友，秦王愿意吗？
ignore it?
忽略它？
Let me go!
让我走！
King of Qin.
秦王。
Why?
为什么？
The lieutenant fell ill.
中尉病倒了。
The situation is bad.
情况很糟糕。
The lieutenant fell ill?
中尉生病了？
Find a doctor.
找医生。
Why do you want to see me?
你为什么想见我？
Since childhood, I checked the lieutenant's pulse.
我从小就给 中尉检查脉搏。
I understand his body condition.
我了解他的身体状况。
This time,
这次，
the situation is strange.
情况很奇怪。
He suddenly had a high fever.
他突然发高烧。
I do acupuncture and give medicine,
我做针灸 、喂药，
but not effective.
但没有效果。
Today,
今天，
lieutenant already
中尉已经
is in a coma.
处于昏迷状态。
Honourable.
尊敬的。
Hurry up to see him.
快点去见他吧。
I've never seen it
我从没见过
this strange terrible disease.
这种奇怪可怕的疾病。
You can't even treat him,
你甚至不能治疗他，
so you should find a doctor.
所以你应该找医生。
You...
你...
King Qin's coldness.
秦王的冷漠。
Anything,
任何事物，
Cui Family Army
崔家军
is an ally of the Zhenxi Army, right?
是镇西军的盟友吧？
Since we conspired,
自从我们密谋以来，
you shouldn't treat him like this.
你不应该 这样对待他。
You are cruel.
你很残忍。
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
Taozi.
Taozi.
Taozi!
Taozi!
You...
你...
Why are you so cruel?
你为何如此残忍？
Don't pretend anymore.
别再假装了
I know
我知道
about your tricks
关于你的伎俩
You want to make me sick,
你想让我生病，
but did not succeed.
但没有成功。
So, you made him fall ill,
所以，你让他生病了，
not?
不是？
Nothing to do with me this time.
这次与我无关。
I swear.
我发誓。
(It's good to go see him.)
（很高兴能去见他。）
(What if he really is sick?)
（如果他真的生病了怎么办？）
How much.
多少。
You must survive.
你必须生存。
I told people to ride fast horses
我告诉人们要骑快马
to report to the commander in chief.
向总司令报告。
So...
所以...
He will arrive soon.
他很快就会到达。
Miss must survive.
小姐必须活下去。
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
I'm outside.
我在外面。
The moon is shining and there are less stars tonight.
今晚月亮很亮 ，星星较少。
Master Shiqi, let's go.
士奇大师，我们走吧。
Go on patrol.
去巡逻​​吧
Aren't you busy talking?
你不是忙着说话吗？
that you want to sleep?
你想睡觉吗？
You find various excuses so you don't have to patrol.
你会找各种借口， 这样你就不用巡逻了。
Why?
为什么？
You are very proactive today.
今天你非常主动。
Tonight is not the same.
今晚不一样。
I am energetic.
我精力充沛。
Let me accompany you on patrol
让我陪你巡逻
so you don't do anything else.
所以你不用做任何其他事情。
What will I do?
我该怎么办？
If you don't want to do anything,
如果你什么都不想做
it's still good.
还是不错的。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
I will be with you all night.
我会 整夜和你在一起。
Check the presence of soldiers at six in the morning.
早上六点检查士兵在场。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Go away.
离开。
Tonight,
今晚，
we will patrol
我们将巡逻
in all corners.
在各个角落。
How much.
多少。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Taozi, I have cooked medicine.
桃子，我煮药了。
I obey what you say
我听你的话
to buy this medicine
买这个药
at a nearby drug store.
在附近的一家药店。
Then, I sat in the kitchen and cooked this medicine myself.
然后，我就坐在厨房里 ，自己煮了这药。
The timing is right.
时机是对的。
How much.
多少。
The medicine is ready, miss.
小姐，药已经准备好了。
Give me.
给我吗。
Miss will be cured after eating it.
小姐吃了之后就会痊愈。
How much.
多少。
Miss, please.
小姐，请。
Open mouth.
张开嘴。
Miss will be cured after eating it.
小姐吃了之后就会痊愈。
How much.
多少。
I really have no other way.
我实在没有别的办法了。
Please take medicine, miss.
小姐，请吃药。
How much.
多少。
Taozi.
Taozi.
I will call Mr. Shiqi now.
我现在就给士奇先生打电话。
I will force him
我会强迫他
come this time.
这次来吧。
Do not go.
不要去。
He's a cold person.
他是一个冷酷的人。
Why did you call him to come?
你为什么叫他来？
So.
所以。
Surely he didn't know
他肯定不知道
that Lieutenant He's condition is dire.
何中尉的情况很危急。
Mr. Shiqi is not that kind of person.
士奇先生不是那样的人。
Please let me take care of you here.
请让我在这里照顾你。
I will command the whole army
我将指挥全军
to increase alertness.
以提高警觉性。
He is very sick now.
他现在病得很重。
Can't let outsiders know
不能让外人知道
and take a chance.
并抓住机会。
Good.
好的。
Oh yes.
哦是的。
After I got home,
我回到家后，
you can go back first
你可以先回去了
Otherwise, you will miss the attendance check in the army.
否则，你将错过 军队的考勤。
So.
所以。
I am with you here.
我和你在一起。
You are from the Zhenxi Army.
你是镇西军的。
If the commander-in-chief returns
如果总司令归来
and see the condition of the lady,
看看这位女士的状况，
I'm worried that he will kill you.
我担心 他会杀了你。
Young master.
少爷。
How?
如何？
King Qin hasn't come out yet.
秦王还没出来。
I don't think it's right.
我认为这是不对的。
I didn't think Li Ni
没想到李妮
so cold.
好冷。
Ying looked at him wrongly.
颖错愕地看着他。
Young master.
少爷。
The lieutenant had been poisoned for three days.
中尉已经中毒 三天了。
If he doesn't take the antidote tonight,
如果他今晚不服用解药
his life will be affected
他的生活将会受到影响
even if he eats the cure in the morning.
即使他 早上吃了解药。
Wait again.
再等一下。
Tuan Shiqi.
Tuan Shiqi.
Do not go.
不要去。
It's only one o'clock in the morning.
现在才凌晨一点。
What are you doing back?
你回来做什么？
We have patrolled all the places. Why do you want to stay here?
我们已经巡逻了所有的地方。 你为什么想留在这里？
Patrolling again.
再次巡逻。
Didn't we promise?
我们不是答应过吗？
I will accompany you until the morning.
我会陪你直到早上。
I have something else.
我还有别的事。
What thing?
什么东西？
I haven't read the letter
我还没读过这封信
sent from the capital.
从首都送来的。
You can read it tomorrow.
你明天就可以读了。
It is not an emergency letter.
这不是一封紧急信函。
I want to sleep.
我想睡觉了。
How did you scold me a few nights ago?
前几天晚上你怎么骂我的？
Not tired.
不累。
We are not sleepy.
我们不困。
You did it on purpose, didn't you?
你是故意的，不是吗？
You are right.
你是对的。
I'm deliberately.
我是故意的
Good. Let's continue.
好的。我们继续吧。
Proceed.
继续。
- Go away.
- 离开。
Go away.
离开。
You can't stop me, can you?
你不能阻止我，对吗？
Young master, it's almost dawn.
少爷，天快亮了。
I don't think it's right.
我认为这是不对的。
Ying is really smart,
瑛真的很聪明
but he trusted the wrong person.
但他信错了人。
Tonight, the Cui Family Army has increased vigilance.
今晚，崔家军 提高了警惕。
If we wait until dawn,
如果我们等到天亮
it's hard for me to enter.
我很难进入。
This is the cure.
这就是解药。
Go away.
离开。
Let Ying take the medicine first.
让莹先吃药。
Of.
的。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Why did King Qin come?
秦王为何来？
Is your lieutenant
是你的中尉吗
did you fall sick?
你生病了吗？
Only healthy lieutenant.
只有健康的中尉。
No need to worry, your honor.
不用担心，法官大人。
Is he really sick?
他真的有病吗？
No lah.
不，就是这样。
Your Highness, please keep your temper.
殿下请息怒。
This is the Cui Family Army camp.
这里是崔家军营。
If the noble continues to do this,
如果贵族继续这样做的话
I will tell people
我会告诉人们
drive away the noble.
赶走贵人。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Who are you talking to outside?
你在外面跟谁说话？
How much.
多少。
Slowly.
慢慢地。
Mari.
马里。
Let me see.
让我看看。
I am fine.
我没事。
You must be worried.
你一定很担心。
I am really worried.
我真的很担心。
Ying.
莹。
You did get sick.
你确实生病了。
Which one hurts?
哪个疼？
are you ok now
你现在好了吗
King Qin, don't be like that.
秦王，你别这样。
It's just a mild illness.
这只是一种轻微的疾病。
No need to worry.
不用担心。
Taozi.
Taozi.
You're out for a second.
你已经出去了一会儿。
I want to talk
我想谈谈
with the King of Qin.
与秦王。
How much.
多少。
You just woke up.
你刚刚醒来。
Let me accompany you here.
让我陪你到这里吧。
It's ok. Do not worry.
没关系。不用担心。
Go away.
离开。
Ying.
莹。
You hate me because I cheated on you.
你恨我， 因为我欺骗了你。
These several days,
这几天，
I also think a lot.
我也想了很多。
Even if this happens again,
即使这样的事情再次发生，
I will still do that.
我仍然会这样做。
I don't regret it.
我不后悔。
Because I think
因为我认为
whether he is the great-grandson of the real majesty
他是否是真正陛下的曾孙
or a fake one,
或者是假的，
It's not worth it for you to sacrifice for him.
你为他牺牲不值得。
You are sick now.
你现在病了。
Do not discuss this again.
不要再讨论这个问题了。
When I have a fever
当我发烧时
and didn't realize a few days before,
没想到几天前，
I hope that you can come visit me.
我希望你 能来拜访我。
When someone gets sick,
当有人生病时，
he will become weak.
他会变得虚弱。
My mother died when I was little.
我很小的时候，我的母亲就去世了。
I have less family members too.
我的家人也比较少。
Now, besides dad,
现在，除了爸爸，
you are the closest to me.
你是离我最近的。
At that time, I thought
那时我想
that if you come to see me,
如果你来看我
then it proves that
那么它证明了
you care more about me
你更关心我
from other things
从其他事物
and others.
和别的。
If you come,
如果你来，
I can explain
我可以解释
that's up to you
这取决于你
even if I'm angry.
即使我很生气。
With this, you can too
有了这个，你也可以
understand my feelings next time.
下次理解我的感受。
However, you did not come.
然而，你却没有来。
I know
我知道
that you still scold me
你还骂我
I'm not scolding you.
我不是在骂你。
In my heart,
在我心里，
you are more important than anyone else.
你比任何人都重要。
Honourable,
尊敬的，
don't fool me again
别再愚弄我了
I also want to tell you something
我也想告诉你一件事
honestly.
诚实地。
I want to tell you
我想告诉你
that I don't care
我不在乎
title of King of Qin
秦王的称号
or the commander in chief.
或总司令。
I just want to finish Concubine Xiao's order.
我只是想完成 萧妃的吩咐。
Then, I want to go back to Laolan Border
然后， 我要回老兰边境
with you
与你
We can enjoy the sky there.
我们可以在那里欣赏天空。
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
You can't go back.
你不能回去。
your father
你父亲
is the current emperor.
是现任皇帝。
Sun Jing is dead, the situation is decided.
孙靖死了， 局势已定。
Both your brothers
你们两个兄弟
just like a wild animal.
就像野生动物一样。
Do you want to submit?
您想提交吗？
our country to them?
我们的国家对他们来说？
I have said.
我说了。
After I saved his great-grandson,
我救了他的曾孙后
I will persuade him
我会说服他
to appoint his great-grandson as crown prince.
任命他的曾孙 为皇太子。
How old is his great-grandson this year?
他的曾孙今年多大了？
His great-grandson is still young.
他的曾孙还很年轻。
How are his qualifications and talents?
他的资质和才华如何？
If he becomes a talentless person
如果他变成一个没有才华的人
after he grew up,
当他长大后，
how does he want to lead the country?
他想如何领导这个国家？
His great-grandson is a legitimate descendant.
他的曾孙是合法的后裔。
He should inherit the throne.
他应该继承王位。
After all, he is talented.
毕竟他是有才华的。
There are many more dignitaries
还有很多达官贵人
will help him.
会帮助他。
He will succeed.
他会成功的。
Are both your brothers
都是你兄弟
will let his great-grandson live to adulthood?
会让他的曾孙 活到成年吗？
Anything,
任何事物，
you feel that
你觉得
I have to compete for this throne.
我必须争夺这个王位。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Because I think you are the most suitable
因为我觉得你是最合适的
to lead this country.
领导这个国家。
You are generous and care about this country.
你很慷慨，关心 这个国家。
You have compassion for the people.
你对人民有同情心。
You have great military achievements
你有 伟大的军事成就
and great in controlling the army.
并且善于控制军队。
You restored the kingdom
你恢复了王国
and put down the rebellion.
并平定叛乱。
If you are appointed crown prince,
如果你被任命 为皇太子
magnifier in the balirung draw
balirung 绘图中的放大镜
will not object.
不会反对。
Without a dispute in the draw,
抽签过程中没有出现争议，
people can live happily.
人们可以幸福地生活。
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
You will be
你会
good and responsible emperor.
好又负责任的皇帝。
If you become emperor,
如果你当了皇帝
this country will be peaceful and prosperous
这个国家将会和平繁荣
for decades to come.
未来几十年。
Everyone has their own ambitions.
每个人 都有自己的抱负。
There are people who want to control the whole country,
有人想 控制整个国家，
but I just want to keep my promise.
但我只想信守诺言。
When the situation stabilizes,
当局势稳定后，
I want to protect
我想保护
Laolan border with you.
老兰与你接壤。
What if I
如果我
refused to follow you to the Laolan Border?
不肯跟着你 去老兰边境？
♪If you've forgotten the twinkling light♪
♪如果你忘记了闪烁的光芒♪
♪Tunggu kenangan♪
♪东古肯南甘♪
♪Shattered and sunk♪
♪破碎沉没♪
♪The spots that remain on your heart♪
♪留在心中的斑点♪
♪Penarikan itu♪
♪佩纳里坎伊图♪
♪It's my objection♪
♪我反对♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪如果渴望不被遗忘的话♪
♪Longing to go back to the earliest times♪
♪渴望回到 最初的时光♪
♪The warmth that fate once had♪
♪命运曾经拥有的温暖 ♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪我想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪We once promised♪
♪我们曾经约定♪
♪Even though love hurts me♪
♪尽管爱让我受伤♪
♪I must live for you too♪
♪我也必须为你而活♪
♪Following faces in memories♪
♪追随记忆中的面孔♪
♪Waiting is my obsession♪
♪等待是我的痴迷♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪Terbalikkan 因果报应♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪爱你无怨无悔♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪我愿意把它留给你♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪我一直在等你 回答我♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪Terbalikkan 因果报应♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪爱你无怨无悔♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪我愿意把它留给你♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪我一直在等你 回答我♪